Isack A Ramirez

isack.ramirez1@gmail.com | 210.464.0710 | San Antonio, Texas https://isack-ramirez.github.io/rectPortfolioRedeploy/#/

OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastically seeking an entry-level position in web application development in areas of full stack development to flexibly leverage my strengths in modern JS frameworks for backend web services and web authoring skills for frontend user interfaces along with popular SQL and NoSQL databases to build next-level products.

SUMMARY

Possess over 4 years of combined work experience in commercial and small business construction management for doctor offices and all AquaTots swim centers in San Antonio area, and audio/video systems with web development experience in industry, academia, and freelance. Frequently learning to build technical skills to make future development cutting-edge.

PROGRAM LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Java, JavaScript, React, Express, Node, Bootstrap, HandleBars, SQL, MongoDB, GraphQL and Apollo, HTML, CSS, BCrypt, Twillio, Insomnia, basic Python, currently learning Docker.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Freelance and Academia – San Antonio, TX

09/2018 – Present

IMAGineDrive Full Stack Developer

- In progress of scheduling a demonstration of a web application named IMAGineDrive that was developed with a freelance team for a local Optometrist that would enable doctors, staff, and patients to create individual account, track status of patients orders (glasses, contacts), and notify customers via text of order status.
- Responsible for standing up REST API using Express, used JavaScript for handling user navigating and routing to web services, set up MySQL for record persistence, and implemented Twillio for text message notifications.
- Deployed IMAGineDrive to Heroku, application stack included: JavaScript, Sequelize, Handlebars, Node, MySQL, Insomnia, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, Twillio

IMAGineDeck Full Stack Developer

- Teamed with freelance developers and hobbyists to construct a Hearthstone web application which would leverage the Hearthstone API to allow users to build deck in the site before starting a game.
- Application stack included MongoDB, GraphQL, Apollo, React, Bcrypt, Express; deployed to Heroku.

Bill's PC Full Stack Developer

- Developed a basic Pokémon web application named Bill's PC (with CRUD capabilities) for academia to build technical competency in building simple web requests and integrating the Pokémon API (to pull Pokémon character profiles) and the ProfanityFilter API (for validating user input), and deployed to GitHub.io.
- Technologies involved include: HTML; JavaScript; CSS; AJAX, Poke API; ProfanityFilter API.

Healthcare Construction – San Antonio, TX

10/2018 - Present

Assistant Project Manager

- Constructed website for Health Construction using Bootstrap and Javascript (in the process of upgrading company web presence to something more modern).
- In charge of supervising wide array of subcontracted construction remodeling teams (including: concrete; professional equipment installation; electrical; plumbing; painting; flooring) in areas of customer craftsmanship and standards.
- Periodically report progress to Project Manager; and trusted to handle construction plans, building permits, invoices.
- Routinely manage the procurement of \$3,000 \$16,000 worth of materials (depending on project) and oversee their use.
- Increased client base by interacting with various small businesses through relationship building.

TEAMAV - San Antonio, TX

09/2017 - 10/2018

Audio Video Technician

- Set up equipment for clients who required business accommodations (conferences, business presentations, luncheons, entertainment shows, weddings).
- Provided technical troubleshooting and resolution services in during live events for equipment including: sound mixers, projectors, lights, light boards (networked), soundboards (networked), speakers, XLR cabling, HDMI cabling, monitors.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at San Antonio – San Antonio, TX

04/2021 - 10/2021

• Full Stack Development Certification – Computer Science

San Antonio College – San Antonio, TX

09/2018 - 04/2021

• Associates – Computer Science